Ron Lipps

Front End Web Developer San Diego, Ca rdl.work@gmail.com

OBJECTIVES

A diligent worker seeking a position in a role as a front end or full stack developer leveraging 7+ years of experience in Javascript, HTML, CSS, PHP and education with modern frameworks and libraries. Certified and fully trained in graphical, video and audio editing with the full suite of Adobe products, I am equally comfortable with many other proprietary, open source and web-based tools.

EXPERIENCE

SearchOptics, San Diego

Senior Web developer: (2013 - 2019)

- Responsibilities included building and maintaining custom websites, custom client & company portfolio themes using Search Optics' proprietary CMS.
- Invented a new development process for reusable, modular and theme-swappable components that would come to be trade marked as "Smart Blocks".
- Theme templates created using Smart Blocks consume user-editable branding styles and automatically
 adjust to minor content changes allowing non-developer CMS users to build sites and custom pages
 quickly and efficiently.
- Created themes using Smart Blocks that could be built, tested and ready to deploy in 4 weeks as opposed to 2-3 months using the former prescribed process.
- Created 12 portfolio themes and over 30 program themes.

Technology used:

HTML5, CSS3, VanillaJS, jQuery, Node, PHP, Doctrine, AJAX, JSON, RESTful API, MySQL, Elastic Search, CouchDB, GIT, JIRA, NetSuite, Photoshop, PHPStorm, Brackets, Docker, VirtualBox, Mac, Windows, Ubuntu, CentOS and MS Office.

Archaio, San Diego

Product Manager: (2010 - 2012)

- Responsibilities included general Office Management, supervision of all Dev and QA projects while supporting requests from Operations and other clients.
- Introduced Agile methodologies and incorporated RAD principles into Archaio's development lifecycle.
- Maintained a record of meeting or exceeding projected timelines.

Software Quality Assurance Manager: (2002 - 2010)

- Responsibilities included supervision of all ongoing QA as well as process and protocol for the testing of Archaio's web and desktop applications suite.
- Introduced industry standard testing methods and tools; regression testing, threshold testing, browser automation testing and enforced reporting standards.
- Eliminated the recurrence of major bugs being reported from the field via Help Desk within 2 dev cycles while maintaining or exceeding timelines.

Help Desk Manager: (2001 - 2008)

- Responsibilities included the supervision/support of a small 24 hour Help Desk team, documentation for the purpose of training & online user resources and the occasional support of QA projects and Desktop support.
- Implemented a simple GUI and database in Microsoft Excel application to ensure a complete ticket for each incoming support request is created.
- Results of a simple searchable ticket system with alerts for following up facilitated expedient escalation and eliminated dropped support requests.

Technology used:

HTML, Javascript, Selenium, MS Visual Interdev, MS Office, Bugzilla, Clonezilla, NortonGhost, GIMP and Blender 3D.

EDUCATION

SDCE, San Diego — *Interactive Media Certificate Program*

2012

Adobe Suite, Graphical and Web Design

CompTIA A+ N+

2001

Desktop, Server and Networking Certifications